export const items = [
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-c.mp3",
        options: ["c", "ş", "ç", "j"],
        correctAnswer: "c",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ch.mp3",
        options: ["ç", "ş", "g", "ğ"],
        correctAnswer: "ç",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-gh.mp3",
        options: ["ğ", "g", "k", "c"],
        correctAnswer: "ğ",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-j.mp3",
        options: ["j", "z", "c", "d"],
        correctAnswer: "j",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-l.mp3",
        options: ["l", "r", "b", "u"],
        correctAnswer: "l",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-m.mp3",
        options: ["m", "n", "b", "p"],
        correctAnswer: "m",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-n.mp3",
        options: ["n", "g", "m", "h"],
        correctAnswer: "n",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-p.mp3",
        options: ["p", "b", "v", "h"],
        correctAnswer: "p",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-r.mp3",
        options: ["r", "l", "a", "e"],
        correctAnswer: "r",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-s.mp3",
        options: ["s", "z", "j", "c"],
        correctAnswer: "s",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-sh.mp3",
        options: ["ç", "ş", "s", "z"],
        correctAnswer: "ş",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-t.mp3",
        options: ["t", "d", "z", "c"],
        correctAnswer: "t",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-v.mp3",
        options: ["v", "b", "f", "m"],
        correctAnswer: "v",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-y.mp3",
        options: ["y", "u", "ı", "j"],
        correctAnswer: "y",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-z.mp3",
        options: ["z", "v", "y", "j"],
        correctAnswer: "z",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-c.mp3", "c"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ch.mp3", "ç"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-j.mp3", "j"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-sh.mp3", "ş"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-gh.mp3", "ğ"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-g.mp3", "g"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-l.mp3", "l"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-r.mp3", "r"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-m.mp3", "m"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-n.mp3", "n"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-p.mp3", "p"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-t.mp3", "t"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-s.mp3", "s"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-sh.mp3", "ş"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-j.mp3", "j"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ch.mp3", "ç"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-v.mp3", "v"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-b.mp3", "b"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-h.mp3", "h"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-f.mp3", "f"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-y.mp3", "y"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-j.mp3", "j"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ch.mp3", "ç"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-c.mp3", "c"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-z.mp3", "z"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-j.mp3", "j"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-v.mp3", "v"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-c.mp3", "c"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-c.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'c'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ch.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'ç'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-gh.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'ğ'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-j.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'j'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-l.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'l'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-m.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'm'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-n.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'n'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-p.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'p'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-r.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'r'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-s.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 's'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-sh.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'ş'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-t.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 't'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-v.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'v'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-y.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'y'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-z.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'z'
    },
];



const shuffleArray = (array) => {
    const shuffledArray = [...array];
    for (let i = shuffledArray.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
        const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
        [shuffledArray[i], shuffledArray[j]] = [shuffledArray[j], shuffledArray[i]];
    }
    return shuffledArray;
};

const shuffleOptions = (questions) => {
    return questions.map((question) => {
        if (question.qType === 'listening-multi') {
            return { ...question, options: shuffleArray(question.options) };
        } else if (question.qType === 'listening-matching') {
            return { ...question, pairs: shuffleArray(question.pairs) };
        } else {
            return question; // Handle other question types if needed
        }
    });
};

export const shuffledTurkish1bQ = shuffleArray(shuffleOptions(items));